All right, no peeking.
눈뜨면 안 돼
No peeking.
눈뜨기 없다
실눈 뜨지 마
No peeking. No peeking!
All right, but you better be
wearing clothes when I open my eyes.
알았어, 대신 눈 떴을 때
옷 벗고 있기만 해봐라
All right. Open your eyes!
됐어, 눈 떠!
Sweet mother of all
that is good and pure!
요정이라도 왔다 간 거야?
Days of our Lives
picked up my option!
'우리들의 삶'에서
배역을 따냈어!
- 축하해!
- 알아!
-Congratulations!
-I know!
Now we can watch Green Acres
the way it was meant to be seen.
이젠 '그린 에이커'를
생생하게 즐길 수 있겠다
어느 쪽이 내 거야?
So which one is mine?
Whichever one you want, man.
Whichever one you want!
네 맘대로 골라
앉고 싶은 데 앉으라고
Not that one.
그거 말고
Oh, yes!
이런!
Oh, yeah! That's the stuff.
그래, 바로 이거야
준비됐나?
Do we dare?
We dare.
준비완료
The One Where Ross and Rachel...You Know
I can't believe two cows
made the ultimate sacrifice...
암소 두 마리의 희생 덕에
편하게 앉아서 보는 줄 알아
...so you could watch TV
with your feet up.
이건 책상다리 암소야
No, they were chair-shaped cows.
의자가 안 됐어도
책상다리가 될 팔자라고
They never would have survived
in the wild.
This screen is amazing.
Dick Van Dyke is practically life-size.
화면 진짜 끝내준다
딕 반다이크가 실물 크기네
로즈 마리는 작은 화면으로
보는 게 더 낫겠지?
Rose Marie belongs on
a smaller screen, doesn't she?
- 안녕, 얘들아
- 어서 와
Hi, you guys.
Hey, you.
- 안녕, 자기?
- 안녕
How was your day?
- 오늘 어땠어?
- 여느 때와 같지
You know, pretty much the usual.
태양은 빛나고
새들은 지저귀고
Sun shining, birds chirping.
정말? 나도 그랬어
Really? Mine too.
자기들, 나도 그랬어
Hey, cool! Mine too!
I gotta get to the museum.
박물관에 가 봐야 해
오늘 밤에 볼까?
So I'll see you tonight?
좋아
Bye, guys!
- 나 간다
- 잘 가
오늘 밤?
Tonight?
- 이것 봐
- 비켜 줘
- 오늘 밤에 뭘 한다고?
- 첫 공식 데이트
-What's tonight?
-Our first official date.
Our first date.
우리의 첫 데이트라고
여보세요?
Hello?
Hi.
네?
오늘 밤 내 음식 날라준다며?
내 얘긴 귓등으로 흘렸어?
You're supposed to waitress for me?
My catering thing?
-Any of that trigger anything?
-Oh, God, Monica. I forgot!
이런, 잊고 있었네!
하지만 첫 데이트인데
This is our first date.
엄마가 소개해 주신 일이야
-Yes, but my mom got me this job.
-I can be a waitress!
서빙은 나도 할 수 있어!
할 수 있다고
고마워
정말 고마워, 피비
Thank you, thank you.
See? Phoebe! Phoebe!
Really, Pheebs?
You'd have to be an actual waitress.
진짜야?
진짜 웨이트리스가 돼야 해
네 노래 '난 맥주 컵' 같음 안 돼
This can't be like your
"I can be a bear cub" thing.
나도 할 수 있어, 볼래?
I can be a waitress.
Okay, watch this.
Give me two number ones,
86 the bacon...
1번 메뉴 둘! 베이컨 푹 익혀서
차에서 기다리니까 서둘러요!
...one Adam and Eve on a raft
and wreck them!
제임스 본드잖아!
It's James Bond!
- 늦어서 죄송해요
- 괜찮아요, 어서 와요
-Sorry we're late.
-That's okay. Come on in.
모니카 겔러는 안 오나?
온다고 했는데
Is Monica Geller coming?
I was told she was.
버크 박사님, 저예요
Dr. Burke, it's me.
Monica?
네가 모니카냐?
이럴 수가, 옛날의 너는...
My God! You used to be so....
I mean, you've
You must have lost like....
그러니까...
많이 날씬해졌구나
- 아주 멋지다
- 고맙습니다
You look great.
Thank you.
This is Phoebe.
She'll be helping me.
친구 피비예요
절 도와 주러 왔어요
Nice to meet you.
반가워요
- 어떻게 지내니?
- 잘지냈죠, 아저씨는요?
-So how you been?
-Great. How have you been?
바바라와 헤어졌지만
고개 까딱할 필요 없어
Obviously you know
Barbara and I split up...
...or you wouldn't do the head tilt.
'까딱'이요?
The head tilt?
이혼하고 나서 안부 물을 때
다들 동정의 고갯짓으로
Since the divorce,
everybody asks how I am...
...with a sympathetic head tilt.
"How you doing? You okay?"
'잘지내시죠?' 하지
- 안되셨네요
- 괜찮아
I'm sorry.
나도 똑같이 대처한단다
It's fine.
Believe me, I do it too.
대답할 때 고개를 끄덕이면서
'난 괜찮아'라고 해
I always answer with the
"I'm okay" head bob. "I'm okay."
"You're sure?"
'정말요?' 하면
'물론이죠' 하지
"Yeah, I'm fine."
음악을 틀으마
CD기를 샀거든
I gotta set up the music.
I got a new CD changer.
이혼 후 남은 건 CD 4장뿐이지
Of course, the divorce only left
me with four CDs to change.
안됐어요
That's too bad.
생존은 가능해
I'll survive.
Two larges, extra cheese on both.
큰 걸로 두 개
치즈를 듬뿍 얹어서요
잘 들어요
19호 초인종은 누르지 말아요
But listen...
...don't ring the buzzer for 19.
Ring 20. Geller/Greene.
20호를 눌러요 '겔러와 그린'
걔네들이 열어 줄 거예요
They'll let you in, okay?
우리 집 거 누르면
팁은 없을 줄 알아요
If you buzz our door,
there's no tip for you.
좋아요, 고마워요
Okay, thanks.
피자 해결됐어
일어날 필요 없다고 했잖아
Pizza's on the way.
I told you we wouldn't have to get up.
What if we have to pee?
오줌 마려우면?
I'll cancel the sodas.
음료수는 취소해야겠다
여기서 뭐 하세요?
아저씨를 위한 파티예요!
Get back out there.
It's your party!
But they're so dull!
They're all ophthalmologists.
재미없어 죽겠어!
안과 의사들은 따분하다고
아저씨도 안과 의사잖아요
You're an ophthalmologist.
부모님이 원하셨던 일이야
난 보안관이 되고 싶었지
Because my parents wanted me to be.
I wanted to be a sheriff.
백차와 백내장 얘기
정말 재밌네요
That's funny.
Cadillac, cataract. I get it.
갖다 드릴게 그냥 계세요!
But you stay out there!
-You see?
-I tell you what.
- 봤지?
- 알겠어요
먼저 가 계시면 금방
요리 갖고 가서 구해 드리죠
I'll come get you in five minutes
with some sort of kebob emergency.
그래, 꼭 와야 돼
Better.
Oh, God, here we go.
내가 간다
Hey, want to see them go nuts?
저들이 발광하는 거 볼래?
어디 보라고
Watch this.
Who needs glasses?
글라스 필요한 사람?
You are so smitten.
- 너 홀딱 반했구나?
- 아냐
I am not!
Oh, you are so much
the smitten kitten.
홀딱 반한 고양이 꼴이데 뭐
- 데이트 신청해
- 버크 박사님께?
-You should ask him out.
-Dr. Burke?
I don't think so.
I mean, like, he's a grownup.
그건 안 돼
박사님은 어른이잖아
So? You two are
totally into each other.
그래서?
서로 관심 있잖아
부모님의 친구 분이야
He's a friend of my parents.
He's like 20 years older than me.
나보다 20살은 더 드셨어
그래서 다신 안 볼 거야?
So you're never gonna see him again?
Not never.
'다신'은 아니지
I'm gonna see him tomorrow
at my eye appointment.
내일 눈 검사 받기로 했거든
-Didn't you just get your eyes checked?
-Yeah, but you know...
- 너 눈 검사 싫어했잖아
- 그래, 하지만...
... 27 is...
27살이면
눈이 위험할 시기라고
...a dangerous eye age.
I'm not saying it was a bad movie.
I'm just saying it was a little...
재미없다고는 안 했어
이해하기 어려웠을 뿐이야
... hard to follow.
I told you there'd be subtitles.
- 그러게 자막을 읽어야지
- 알아
I know.
첫 데이트인데 안경을
쓰고 싶진 않았어
I just didn't want to wear
my glasses on our first date.
Monica?
모니카?
키스할 때 동생 이름을
외치지 않으면 훨씬 고맙겠어
It would help when I'm kissing
if you didn't shout my sister's name.
Honey, I'm just checking.
있나 확인하려고
-Monica?
-Mon?
- 모니카?
왜?
What?
- 왜 그래?
- 미안해
I'm sorry.
그냥... 손이 아래로
내려가니까 이상해서
It's just, when you moved
your hands down to my butt...
...it was, like, "Whoa!
Ross' hands are on my butt!"
'로스 손이 내 엉덩이에 있다! '
- 미안해
- 그게 웃은 이유야?
And that's funny. Why?
Well, it's not.
아냐, 내가 좀 긴장했나 봐
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm just nervous.
I mean, it's you.
네가...
아니, 우리가 지금...
You know, it's us.
선을 넘으려 하고 있잖아
그건 대 사건이야
We're crossing that line.
It's sort of a big thing.
그래, 그건 알지만
폭소 대 사건일 줄은 몰랐네
Well, I know it's big.
I just didn't know it was ha-ha big.
이번엔 근처에도 안 갔어
Okay, my hands were
nowhere near your butt.
I know, I know, I know!
알아, 알아, 안다고!
I was thinking about when
they were there the last time.
방금 전에 어디 있었는지
생각하고 있었어, 미안
좋아, 약속해
이제 안 웃을게
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Okay, look! I promise.
I won't laugh anymore.
Put your hands back there.
- 어디 다시 해봐
- 아냐, 이젠 못하겠어
No, see, now I can't.
- 부끄러워졌어
- 한 번만 뻔뻔해져 봐
-I feel self-conscious.
-Just one cheek.
기분이 사라졌다니까
The moment's gone.
- 손 내밀어, 내가 뒤로 돌게
- 참 낭만적이다
-I'll back up into your hands.
-That's romantic.
- Touch it.
-No.
- 어서 만져
- 싫어
-Oh, come on, squeeze it.
-No!
- 꽉 잡아 보라니까
- 싫어!
- 그럼 문질러 볼래?
- 아니
Rub it?
왜 이래?
엉덩이를 꽉 움켜 줘!
Oh, come on!
Would you just grab my ass?
Wow! Look at that!
The car is on fire...
저것 좀 봐!
차에 불이 붙어도...
기적의 왁스만 있으면
비싼 페인트칠이 보호돼
...yet somehow
its expensive paint job...
...is protected by the Miracle Wax.
You've got a Cheeto
on your face, man.
배고플 때 먹으려고 붙여 놨냐?
- 안녕?
Aren't you supposed
to be out with Rachel?
레이첼하고 데이트하기로
하지 않았어?
그건 14시간 전 일이지
That was 14 hours ago.
So how'd it go?
어땠는데?
Have you ever been, you know,
fooling around with a girl...
분위기 잡는데 갑자기
웃어대는 여자 봤어?
...and she started laughing?
1982년에 봤지
But it was 1982...
...and my Flock of Seagulls haircut
was tickling her chin.
내 까까머리가 그녀의
목덜미를 간지럽혔거든
- 레이첼이 웃었어?
- 응
She laughed at you?
I've been wanting this
since ninth grade typing.
중학교 때부터 오늘을
얼마나 기다려 왔는데
완벽하길 바랬는데...
잘되길...
And I just want it to be perfect...
...and right and....
레이저빔을 쏘는데도
왜 페인트가 멀쩡하지?
Why isn't that laser beam
cutting through the paint?
- 기적의 왁스를 발랐거든!
- 기적 그 자체라고
-It's the Miracle Wax!
-lt certainly is a miracle.
Hi, you guys.
안녕, 얘들아
- 안녕?
Listen, I was thinking about....
내가 생각해 봤는데...
Can you guys speak up?
좀 크게 얘기할래?
TV 때문에 잘 안 들려
It's harder for us to hear you
when you lower your voice.
어제는 정말 미안했어
보상하고 싶어
I'm sorry about last night.
I really want to make it up to you.
보상은 무슨...
어떻게?
There's no need to make it up
How?
Well, I was thinking
maybe a romantic dinner...
낭만적인 저녁식사 어때?
...with candles and wine.
촛불과 와인이 있는...
그 다음 우리 집에 와서
디저트를 먹는 거야
And then maybe going
back to my place...
...for dessert.
훌륭한 생각이야
That sounds...
... perfect?
What's this?
- 이게 뭐야?
- 맥주 좀 갖다 줄래?
Would you get us a couple of beers?
I'm going to look into your eyes now.
네 눈을 들여다봐야겠다
Really?
정말요?
그게 내 일이야
That's my job.
All right.
좋아, 위를 봐
Look up.
Look down.
내려다보고
눈을 뜨고 내려다봐야지
Now, open your eyes and look down.
좋아, 빛을 쳐다봐
That's right.
Look into the light.
Now look at me.
이젠 날 봐
다됐다!
Your eyes look good.
Those are good eyes.
이상 없어
눈이 아주 좋구나
저도 좋게 느껴져요
Good. They feel good.
In my head.
머리에서요
- 만나서 반갑다
- 저도요
-lt was great to see you.
-You too.
You too.
나도
안녕히 계세요
Goodbye.
- 안약!
- 네?
Drops!
여기 안약 있다
공짜야
Here, they're free.
Thanks.
고마워요
이제 가야겠어요
I better be going.
- 다음에 보지
- 안약 고마워요
Yeah, I'll see you later.
Thanks again.
너희 같은 게으름뱅이들은
이 의자에서 몰아내야 해
We have to get you lazy boys
out of these chairs.
You should go outside and be with
the three-dimensional people.
밖에 나가서 살아 있는
사람들과 어울려
No. Inside good.
싫어, 안이 좋아
Outside bad.
밖은 싫어
너흰 정말 구제불능이야
You guys are so pathetic.
내가 좋아하는 거다!
Oh, Xanadu!
She's one of us now.
이제 우리편이네
- 안녕, 얘들아
- 안녕
잘 자라는 인사를 하려고
들렀어
We just wanted to stop by
and say good night.
Good night.
잘 자!
뭐야, 고개도 안 돌려?
They won't even turn their heads.
All right, you guys.
I'm taking off my shirt.
좋아, 얘들아
나 옷 벗는다
She's lying.
거짓말이야
Stop sending food to our apartment!
우리 집으로 배달 좀 시키지 마!
Why are you dressed up?
옷은 왜 차려입었어?
너만 데이트 있는 게
아닌가 본데
You're not the only one
with a date.
-What? You have a date? Who with?
-No one.
데이트를 해? 누구랑?
아무도 아냐
뭐야, 이름이 뭔데?
Come on, what's his name?
Nothing.
- 아니라니까
- 말해 줘
Come on, tell me.
알았어, 나 진심이란 거 알아둬
All right, but I'm very excited
about this, okay?
So promise you won't get
big-brothery and judgmental.
오빠 행세를 하거나
도덕적인 잣대로 판단하지 마
약속해, 누구야?
I promise. What?
- 리차드 버크
- 그게 누군데?
-It's Richard Burke.
-Who's Richard Burke?
버크 박사님?
Dr. Burke?
버크 박사님과 데이트를 해?
You have a date with Dr. Burke?
Why? Why? Why...
왜? 왜? 왜...
...should that bother me?
내가 싫어할 이유는 없지
나도 그가 좋아
형님 같거든, 아버지의 형님
I love that man.
He's like a...
...a brother to Dad.
밝고 세련되고 지금까지 중에
최고로 섹시해
He is the brightest, most sophisticated,
sexiest man I've ever been with.
Dr. Burke is sexy?
- 버크 박사가 섹시해?
- 그럼, 당연하지!
Oh, God! Absolutely!
Damn!
It's the museum again.
Can l?
또 박물관이야
-Dr. Burke kissed me once.
-When?
- 그분이 내게 키스했어
- 언제?
내가 7살 때
When I was 7, I crashed my bike
right out in front of his house...
자전거를 타고 그의 집 앞을
지나다 넘어졌는데
...and to stop me from crying,
he kissed me right here.
울고 있는 날 불러서는
여기다 키스해 줬어
- 운도 더럽게 좋구나!
- 알아
-Oh, you are so lucky!
-I know.
오스트랄로피테쿠스는
그렇게 전시하면 안 돼
Australopithecus isn't supposed
to be in that display.
아냐, 아니라고
호모 하빌루스가 서야지
No, Homo habilis was erect.
Australopithecus was never fully erect.
오스트랄로피테쿠스는
설 수가 없다고
긴장했나 보지 뭐
Well, maybe he was nervous.
말도 안 돼!
Oh, look!
I can't believe this!
호모 하빌루스는
도구를 사용할 줄 몰라
Homo habilis can't use tools yet,
and they've got him with clay pots?
그런데 토기를 갖다 놔?
아예 전자렌지를 갖다 놓지
Why don't they just
give him a microwave?
I'm sorry this is taking so long.
기다리게 해서 미안해
이렇게 늦어질 줄 몰랐어
저녁은 먹을 수 있을 거야
It's longer than I expected.
We will have dinner.
- 난 괜찮아
- 칼!
That's okay.
Karl!
Oh, God.
- 세상에, 이게 미셸이에요?
- 응
-Wow! Is that Michelle?
-Yep.
고등학교 졸업한 후로
못 봤어요
I've not seen her since
high-school graduation.
그날 밤 걔가 얼마나 취했...
Oh, my God, that night
she got so dru
Emotional.
좀 흥분했죠
You know, she's having another baby.
또 아기를 가졌어
-I thought she just had one.
-No, no. Henry's almost 2.
- 얼마 전에 하나 낳았잖아요
- 아냐, 헨리는 두 살이 다돼가
말도 하고 별거 다하지
바로 얘야
And he's talking
and everything. Here.
전에 친할아버지보다
내가 더 좋다고 하더라고
The other day he told me he liked me
better than his other grandpa.
사실 걔 친할아버지는
술주정뱅이거든
In all fairness, his other
grandpa's a drunk, but still....
벌써 할아버지시군요
You're a grandpa.
그래
Are we nuts here?
뭐 문제될 거 있나?
글쎄요, 그럴지도 모르죠
I don't know. Maybe.
그 옛날 몰래 오줌 눴던
풀장 주인과 데이트를 하니...
I mean, I'm dating a man
whose pool I once peed in.
I didn't need to know that.
그런 고백할 필요 없어
I guess 21 years is a lot.
한 21년은 차이 나지?
I mean, hell, I'm a whole person
who can drink older than you.
내 말은...
너희보다 그만큼
술을 많이 마셨다는 거야
그래요
그러니까...
- 그러니까 우린...
- 그래
So maybe we should just....
아마도...
Maybe....
Wow.
This really sucks.
- 기분이 엉망이에요
- 정말 그렇구나
Yeah, it sure does.
당장 어떤 결정을 내려야
하는 건 아니잖아요?
We don't really have to decide
anything right now, do we?
그럼, 서두를 필요 없지
No, there's no rush or anything.
-Pizza delivery!
-Oh, I'm gonna kill those guys!
- 피자 왔습니다!
- 쟤네들을 어떻게 죽여?
레이첼?
I'm done.
다 끝났어
그래, 소렌티노도 영업 끝났어
Yeah, well, you know what?
So is Sorentino's.
미안해
다른 데를 찾는 건 어때?
I'm sorry.
Why don't we find someplace else?
늦었어, 다 문닫을 시간이야
다음으로 미뤄야겠다
It's late. Everything will be closed.
We'll do it another night.
- 안 돼, 그럴 순 없어
- 그럴 수 없다고?
No, no, we won't.
We won't?
이리 와
Come on.
좋아, 그거 죽은 거 맞지?
Okay, that's dead, right?
뭘 할 건데?
What are we doing?
-Do you want Cranapple or Cran-Grape?
-Grape.
- 사과맛, 아님 포도맛?
- 포도맛
앉아
Okay, now...
...sit.
Oh, my God!
오 마이 갓!
Billions of years ago,
Earth was only
10억 년 전에 지구는...
미안
Sorry.
뭘 보면 돼?
So what are we looking at?
저 큰 별 옆에 작은
별무리 보여?
Well, you see that little cluster
of stars next to the big one?
That is Ursa Major.
큰곰자리야
-Really?
-No idea. It could be.
- 정말?
- 몰라, 그럴 거야
오래 기다리게 해서
정말 미안해
Listen, I'm sorry
I had to work tonight.
Oh, that's okay.
괜찮아
자긴 기다릴 가치가 있어
You were worth the wait.
단지 오늘 밤만이 아냐
And I don't just mean tonight.
안 웃네?
You're not laughing.
웃을 기분 아냐
This time it's not so funny.
맙소사!
Oh, God!
Honey?
자기... 괜찮아?
That's okay.
왜?
What?
아냐, 자기가 터뜨린 건
주스 팩이라고
Oh, no. You just rolled
over the juice box.
하느님, 감사합니다!
Thank God!
잘 잤어?
Hey, you.
I can't believe I'm waking up
next to you.
네 옆에서 잠을 깨다니
믿어지지가 않아
I know. It is pretty unbel
나도 믿어지지가...
- 왜?
- 우리만 있는 게 아냐
We're not alone.
화재 경보야?
Is that the fire alarm?
응
It's not warm yet.
We still have time.
안 뜨겁네
아직 시간 있어
-Cool.
-Yeah, yeah. Cool!
- 좋아
- 그래, 좋아!